<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Anthony Alaribe</title>
    <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Anthony Alaribe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 15:20:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tonyalaribe.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Should we be normal?</title>
      <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 15:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/normal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, I got caught up in a conversation with another awesome friend of mine. I wouldn’t mention her name this time, and yeah its a “She”.  It started with a statement she made, about how I and my friend Irhose are very out of this world and unrealistic. How our dreams and the ideas we come up with  are not so relevant in our immediate society, i.e Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I’m a programming addict. I love building things, but since I’m limited in terms of resources, I stick to programming, where I can let my ideas come alive with just my time, and no money spent of parts like micro controllers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Irhose on the other hand is obsessed with the brain. I wouldn’t be far fetched if i say he knows more about the brain than a lot of neuro scientists around. His limitation too, is resources. With so many hypothesis’ to be proven, and no research lab around that would listen to an 18 year old undergraduate, he’s stuck to learning as much about the brain as possible, from the interne, and other people’s research works, as his unproven hypothesis’ keep piling, or get proven by other scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t stop there. We still have big dreams to change the world, just in different ways. Irhose is more interested in changing mindsets, while i’m more interested in changing the world by making certain things available to everyone, and solving the problems the problems man faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, back to the post. The conversation did turn into a slight argument. Her dream is simple, to be rich. She is a medical student on the path of becoming a medical doctor, probably because in Nigeria, medical doctors are well paid and have good job security. So, she’s NORMAL. Everyone in existence wants to be rich, but only a very few have a reason to be rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, is it OK to be just normal? Living your life based on standards made by everyone else? Well, it depends. Its OK for a lot of people, not not for everyone, and definitely not for me. In Nigeria, everyone aspires to be either a doctor, lawyer or engineer, which is not a bad thing, but their reasons, are what might not be so acceptable. Everyone wants to go through those carear options, because thats what the society seems to accept. They know that there is good job security in those areas, so they push it on the younger generation. Young people are not encouraged to dream of anything that hasn’t already been
 tried and proven as perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This culture makes everyone let go of their dreams and carry the single dream of being RICH. The goal behind everyone’s ambition is to be rich, not to fulfil any passions. But then, when you get the money, what next? Your life remains like that of everyone else; Working, getting paid, getting broke by month end, and then waiting to get paid again, with no feeling of fulfilment. And when you try to analyse where all the money has been going to, you realise that the more money you got, the more your needs rose to use up the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, its OK to be rich, and money was created to be spent, but money shouldn’t be the goal, but rather a tool, and spending the money should be able to give you fulfilment, afterall, you worked for it. When you have a passion or dream, you’d even have a reasn to make more money. But you’d more likely be investing it on those passions, and you’d get something everyone else doesn’t, FULFILMENT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead of hiding your dreams or not even having dreams because you think they are unrealistic, you could be different from everyone; Have your realistic job, but still let yourself have a passion or dream that might seem unrealistic to the people around you, with the potential for a more fulfiling life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I and Irhose would be rich eventually, but not for the sake of being rich, but because we have causes and needs that would need lots of money to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World is Ours</title>
      <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/world-is-ours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 22:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/world-is-ours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title of this post is also the name of a song. You probably know it. i mean the 2014 FIFA theme song by David correo, not the song with the same title by Aloe Blac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that the world is ours, seems pretty obvious, but i doubt if most of us really appreciate that fact. For me, i feel like each one of us own this world, not our governments, or the huge brands that make all the noise. We all have a stake in all the available resources, so its left to us to take a claim in some of those resources, and protect those that need protecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a member of a student organisation known as ENACTUS,and i appreciate the fact that it doesnt just encourage us to protect, but also maximise all the world has to offer, #seeopportunities, and tap into them, as a way of taking claim of part of these resources, as entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, appreciating that the world is ours, isnt just for the activists. We can appreciate this in everything we do. We can turn the problems of the world into business opportunities, or actively preventing others from destroying this world which we share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. While writing this post, i had the song playing on repeat, so don’t expect to learn anything here. I’m just pouring out my heart through writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, today is the final day of the enactus 2014 international competition in Beijing, China, and i believe anyone can take cue from enactus students worldwide, on how they are able to turn opportunities into meaningful and lasting change, improving and enhancing this world we share. Let their projects speak for themselves. Visit enactus.org. I hope that serves as your first step to playing a role in improving this world which we share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>