<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014 on Anthony Alaribe</title>
    <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/tags/2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014 on Anthony Alaribe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Anthony Alaribe</author>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 22:15:20 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tonyalaribe.github.io/tags/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A recap of 2014: Projects and Achievements</title>
      <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/recap-2014-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 22:15:20 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Anthony Alaribe</author>
      <guid>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/recap-2014-projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;achievements-2014:5988481b2e3cf16192641bbb3835db96&#34;&gt;Achievements 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learnt Golang, LESS, SASS, TOML, YAML and ANGULAR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I built teaching experience, got my 1st pay check, quit a job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got real life marketting and sales experience ( Nescafe Entrepreneural
Challenge )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learnt about Printing ( Direct Imaging ), designing and printing branding
materials and brochures, including an Annual report for Enactus, so I got  to
be a contractor for Enactus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spoke to the Branch Controller of FCMB, on behalf of Enactus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned to take responsibilities and manage people, with Enactus as a
platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned about JSON resume standard, and designed a graphically enticing
Resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I became badass with linux shell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I installed Arch Linux on my laptop (The hard way, with lots of challenges).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got my first laptop in 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got involved in IDEA and smile (A programming partner).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My insights on Entrepreneurship changed- I got lots of entrepreneural ideas
too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I designed a website for a lecturer, for a sizable sum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I began active blogging on this  blog, officially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned to use the Hugo static blog engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I travelled to, and toured Abia State (Umuahia and Aba), on my own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned to write markdown, which is what this blog is written in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-i-had-for-2014:5988481b2e3cf16192641bbb3835db96&#34;&gt;Goals I had for 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate and do yoga often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excercise dialy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Electronics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Golang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Hausa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Mandarin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build Loki ( An Artificially Intelligent Personal Assistant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- Book rental service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- Wadeva (online interest based social network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;books-that-stood-out-in-2014:5988481b2e3cf16192641bbb3835db96&#34;&gt;Books that stood out in 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad - Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enchantment - Guy Kiwasaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To kill a Moking  Bird - Harper Lee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frost series - Kailin Gow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Perks of being a wallflower - Steven Chbosky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chronicles of Ancient Darkness series - Michelle Paver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-ideas-and-projects-i-started-in-2014:5988481b2e3cf16192641bbb3835db96&#34;&gt;Project Ideas and Projects I started in 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Vision  measurement app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loki(AI chat bot using chatscript)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enactus Angularjs App, connecting to various API&amp;rsquo;s clientside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OddJobs (platform for descovering artisans like electricians, etc around you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wadeva (Interest based social network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Becoming the boss webapp (Student save for graduation app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tonyalaribe.github.io&#34;&gt;tonyalaribe.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kaku.com.ng &lt;a href=&#34;http://kaku-go.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;kaku-go.herokuapp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;madeeasyilozobhie.com&#34;&gt;madeeasyilozobhie.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book renting web app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondary School result, exams answer script and time table management app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-projects-i-got-involved-in:5988481b2e3cf16192641bbb3835db96&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects I got involved in&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/limetext/lime&#34;&gt;Lime -open source sublime text alternative
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shazow/ssh-chat&#34;&gt;ssh-chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite superscript in golang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A recap of 2014: An Essay</title>
      <link>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/recap-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 21:47:16 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Anthony Alaribe</author>
      <guid>http://tonyalaribe.github.io/post/recap-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2014 was supposed to be a really awesome and successful year. In january, I made my first pay check, with which i celebrated my birthday (pool party + pizza after party). Outside my birthday party, which I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even in the flow with, 2014 was dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started depressed, probably a manifestation of lots of things; My emotional
state with a certain girl, being stressed out by my job at pacific ( I was still
working monday to Fridays), my &amp;ldquo;get rich quick&amp;rdquo; scheme, which involved me
designing a wordpress theme for the wordpress theme market (Themeforest); and
designing stock images for &amp;ldquo;Graphic River&amp;rdquo;. I never sold any of these items,
even after working countless hours on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my worst result ever in 2014. The reason; A function of depression and my
job at Pacific. I used the pacific job as a getaway from the world. I had enough
money to not overly worry about money, and it took so much from me that I built
enough stress levels to not worry about my problems (real problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this period at pacific, I achieved &amp;ldquo;nothing&amp;rdquo;, learned no new programming
languages, built no interests in any course I took in school; Although I seemed
to make lots of new acquaintances, it drew me away from relationships I had
already built (My friends in school, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left with my first &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo;, which I shall pay for in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit my job at pacific, just before the Enactus National Competition in July.
I travelled to lagos, only to get news about how horrible my results were. This
had the effect of making me emotionless and non-chalant towards school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without the pacific job, my bad grades extended into the next semester, but
atleast I didn&amp;rsquo;t get another &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo;. I got something worse &amp;ldquo;No A&amp;rdquo;, but I got back a
bit of my lost self esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find the balance between Programming and Medical
Laboratory Science (My major), which I would prefer not to have a career in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the end of the year, I started getting stronger desires to have an
actual second degree in Computer Science or  preferably Artificial Intelligence,
as a way of learning those vital concepts which could guide my research, as
well as a chance to get the &amp;ldquo;1st class&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Peace of Mind&amp;rdquo;. I spent 2014 being
broke most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>